Guide to the Yale Student Papers Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale student papers collection
1840-2014
RU 331
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
37.27
78 boxes, 1 folio folder
10.62
The collection consists of research papers and essays by Yale students. Included are many prize-winning essays.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 47 (YRG 47), Collections documenting teaching and learning in Yale academic programs.
Associated Materials
Related material: Senior Prize Essays from the Department of History, Yale University (RU 170), (Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.)
Custodial History
Gift of multiple donors.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of research papers and essays by Yale students. Included are many prize-winning essays.
Essays; Yale College (1718-1887) -- Students; Yale University -- Students
- Yale student essay collection, 1840-1990; Accession 19ND-A-381
  - Best, Miriam R., "Provincial Responses to Propaganda: Scotland and America in the Age of the American Revolution", John Addison Porter Prize, Third Prize, 54 pp., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Drake, Stuart A.C., "The Statute Of Limitations of 1623: Legislative Design and Problems in Litigation before 1660", Andrew D. White Prize, First Place Tie, 60 pp., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fishman, Robert, "The Reaction to Spain's October Revolution: An Analysis of Three Madrid Newspapers", Andrew D. White Prize-Third Prize, 91 pp., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Harrison, Elizabeth A., "Annie Besant and Marie Stopes: Two Defenses of Contraception", Andrew D. White Prize, First Place Tie, 97 pp., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Karras, Christopher, "Tunnel Vision: The Puritans Look at the Indians", Andrew D. White Prize, Third Prize, 22 pp., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Pruett, Jennifer J., "Captivity Narratives: or Revelations Gleaned from Spine-Tingling Tales of Life with the Wild Indians", John Addison Porter Prize, Second Place, 48 pp., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Rimmel, Lesley A., "Was Cromwell a Moreau? Thomas More and Thomas Cromwell", Andrew D. White Prize, Third Prize, 46 pp., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Yates, Margaret Ann, "The Containment of George Kennan", John Addison Porter Prize, Third Prize, 49 pp., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Pinto Vallejos, Julio, "Urban Revolt in the 14th Century: A Case Study", Andrew D. White Prize, First Place Tie, 67 pp., 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Wilson, Craig A., "Rehearsal for a United Nations: The Hot Springs Conference", John Addison Porter Prize, First Place, 66 pp., 1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Winer, Eric, "Peace-making in 1905: The Diplomacy of the Portsmouth Conference", Andrew D. White Prize, First Place Tie, 134 pp., 1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cowell, Eugene F., "To Change Chinatown: Reform in San Francisco's Chinese Quarter, 1882-1906", John Addison Porter Prize, Second Prize, 82 pp., 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11A)
    General note
    See: Yale Senior Honor Essay No.228
  - Delaney, Barbara J., "Crime and Criminality in the Department of the Seine: 1844-1854", Andrew D. White Prize, Second Prize, 75 pp., 1979 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Kuchta: Joseph Edward, Jr., "The Census of 1840, Slavery, and the Annexation of Texas", John Addison Porter Prize, Second Prize, 68 pp., 1979 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Mandlebaum, Elaine H., "A Case Study of Refugees from the Holocaust Who Settled in New Haven", John Addison Porter Prize, First Prize, 68 pp., 1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Mazo, Ruth Sara, "The Perversion of Conversion: Pagan Survivals and Syncretism in Ninth Century Saxony", Andrew D. White Prize, First Prize, 94 pp., 1979 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Witkin, Merle, "The Evacuation of British Children to the United States During World War II", Andrew D. White Prize, First Prize, 20 pp., 1979 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Zbur, Richard. S., "The Primacy of Bureaucratic Power: American Arms Export Policy: The Soviet Naval Deal, 1936-1939", John Addison Porter Prize, First Prize, 66 pp., 1979 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Biser, Daniel R., "The Department of State and the 'Palestine Problem'", John Addison Porter Prize, First Place Tie, 161 pp., 1980 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Farmer, Sarah, "The Communist Resistance in the Hautevienne", Andrew D. White Prize, First Place, 76 pp., 1980 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Nathans, Eli, "Franz Schegelberger: Nazi Jurist", Andrew D. White Prize, Third Place, 67pp., 1980 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Peck, Sarah E., "Action, Not Pity: The Campaign for a United States Government Response the Nazi Holocaust, 1943-1945", John Addison Porter Prize, Second Place Tie, 73 pp., 1978 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Rome, Adam, "Growing Crops for Profit: American Farmers in a Commercial Age, 1870-1900", John Addison Porter Prize, First Place Tie, 155 pp., 1980 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Schultz, Susan, "When the Gud Times Cum Agyen: Attitudes toward change in popular culture in English 19th century songs", Andrew D. White Prize, Second Place, 93 pp., 1980 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Blume, Peter, "From Indifference to Militancy: Thomas Montgomery and the Corps d'Afrique during the Civil War", John Addison Porter Prize, Second Place Tie, 36 pp., 1978 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Chapman, Nancy, "Isaac Babel and the Ting Ling Weeds in the Garden of Socialist Realism", Andrew D. White Prize, Third Place Tie, 71 pp., 1978 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Gray, Jefferson, "Jimmy Carter and the Popu-list Tradition in Georgia Politics, 1890-1976", John Addison Porter Prize, Second Place Tie, 142 pp., 1978 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Hicks, James B., "Egyptian Monopolies, Ottoman Tariffs, and Western Industry: The Diplomacy and Economics of Syrian Commerce within Europe 1883-1861", Andrew D. White Prize, Third Place Tie, 92 pp., 1978 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Good, David H., "Too many chiefs and not enough Indians: Indian policy in Colorado during the Civil War", Walter McClintock Prize, Tie, 48 pp., 1980 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Lysy, Peter, "Gaining Indian allies: Confederate policy toward the five civilized tribes, 1861", Walter McClintock Prize, Tie, 66 pp., 1980 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Smith, Lorraine, "Education and Liberty: A Study in the Thought of Thomas Jefferson", First Place Tie for both the John Addison Porter Prize and for the Katherine K. Walker Prize, 1980-1981, 55 pp. (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Skinner, Charles, "The Tradition of American Anti-Imperialism and Anglo-American Relations, 1945-1947", First Place Tie for the Katherine K. Walker Prize, 1980-1981, 127 pp. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Wolf, David C., "'To Secure a Convenience': The British Reaction to Communist Ascendancy in China", First Place, Andrew D. White Prize, 89 pp., 1981 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Perkins, Anne G., "Father Coughlin in Crisis: The Bankruptcy of Symbols", First Prize Tie, The John Addison Porter Prize, 72 pp., 1981 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Davis, Jennifer G., "John Collier and the Pueblo Lands Board Act of 1924", McClintock Prize, 1981, 57 pp. (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Luneburg, Thomas R., "John Quincy Adams, Georgia, and the Creek Indians", McClintock Prize 1981, 46 pp., 1980 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Diehl, Peter D., "The Muslims of Norman Sicily: A Failed Experiment in Toleration", Second Place for the Andrew D. White Prize 1981, 69 pp. (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Goldstein, Miriam, "Edouard Drumont: The Mythology of French Antisemitism, 1886-1894", Third Place for the Andrew D. White Prize, 65 pp., 1981 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Bordes, Peter A. "Why Go to College? A Study of the Charter of Yale Undergraduates" 164 pp, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Hopkins, Francis W. (Y. 1918) "The Federal Reserve System and Our South American Trade" Submitted for the Cobden Club Medal 13 pp (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Randolph, Frank H. (Y. 1915) "A History of the National Income Tax" Submitted for the Cobden Club Medal 35 pp (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Underhay, Fulton C. (1938 lds) "Tort Claims in Receiverships" 73 pp, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Daggett, Harriet S (1938 1) "The Community Property System of Louisiana" 166 pp, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Stone, Ferdinand F. (1936 lds) "The Basis of Judicial Relief" 104 pp, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Andrews, Fletcher R. (1941 lds) " Situs of Intangibles in Suits against Nonresident Claimants" 174 pp, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Ylagan, Pedro Y. (1927 lds) "Negotiorum Gestio and Solutio Indebiti under the Roman, Spanish-Philippine, and Anglo-American Laws" 104 pp (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Unidentified: "The Old French Declension" incomplete 24 pp, undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Takei, Soguro: "The Japanese Factory Bill" 70 pp, undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Frankel, Karen R. Y.1982 "Work and Ethnicity in the Gilded Age: The Diary of Michael Campbell" Joint first place John Addison Porter Prize. 59 pp (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Hoxie, Timothy. Y. 1982 "The Federalists & Republicanism: Problems of Popular Government" Joint first prize Katherine K. Walker Prize. 56 pp (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Kochenburger, Peter. Y.1982 "Cycles, Drugs and Rock & Roll: A Study of the Counter Culture and the Hell's Angels Motorcycle Club" Walter McClintock Prize. 66 pp. (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Moore, Martha T. Y. 1982 "Our Town: Company Paternalism and Community Participation in Roebling, New Jersey" Joint first prize John Addison Porter Prize. 64 pp (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Rigdon, Sascha (Sarah). Y. 1984 "The Disagreement between Martin Luther and Desiderius Erasmus" Andrew D. White Prize for freshmen and sophomores. 24 pp, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Effron, Alan. Y. 1984 "Calling Out the Guard: the State Militia and Labor in Late Nineteenth Century America." Andrew D. White Prize for freshmen & sophomores. 24 pp, [1982?] (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Baily, Jess. Y. 1982 "The Poetry of the Past: the Napoleonic Legend. Popular Culture and Politics in France 1815-1851" Joint Andrew D. White Prize for Juniors and Seniors, 83 pp (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Delman, Scott. Y. 1982 "A Study in Frustration: Anthony Eden and the War of the Spanish Obsession" Joint first place Andrew D. White Prize for Juniors and Seniors. 91 pp (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Booth, Wilbur F. Y. 1884 "Proposed Amendments to the Constitution" Douglas Fellowship paper, 1885 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Matheson, Albert McClellan "Chief Justice Marshall and the Federal Constitution" Submitted for John Addison Porter Prize, 1884 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Essays submitted for John Addison Porter Prize, 1902 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Baker, Thorne Y.1903 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Bushong, R. G. Y.1903 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Dewey, George A. Y.1903 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Lehman, Eugene H. Y.1902 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Hamlin, Heitler L. Y.1902 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Sweinhart, Henry L. Y.1902 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - "The Causes & Development of the Texas Revolution" Essays submitted for the John Addison Porter Prize, with index, 1904-1905 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Fawley, J. L. (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Howe, Edmund G. Y.1906 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Jamison, Harold B. Y.1903 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Jones, Robert D. (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Keith, Irenus Y.1905 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Perrin Lee J. (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - "The Public Life of Horace Greeley" Essays submitted for the John Addison Porter Prize, 1904-1905 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Stevens, Carleton H. (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Sands, Merrill B. Y.1906 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Robinson, James N. (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Monzani, John T. (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Merritt, Arron R. Y.1905 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Oberlen, Frank (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - "The Public Life of Horace Greeley" Essays submitted for the John Addison Porter Prize, 1904-1905 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Ewers, James E. Y.1906 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Clark, Robert L. Y.1906 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Borden, John (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - "The Secession of Georgia" Submitted for the John Addison Porter Prize, 1904-1905 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Thomson, Carlyle C. Y.1906 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Thomson, A. Lewis (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Seward, E. Clarkson Y.1906 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Sheehan, Paul (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - "The Secession of Georgia" Submitted for the John Addison Porter Prize, 1904-1905 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - McCullough, Albert S. Y.1905 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Lagerquist, Walter E. (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Goldman, J. Albert Y.1905 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - "Mormon Doctrines in the United States" Submitted for the John Addison Porter Prize (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - Van Tassel, C. B. (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - Rinke, Arthur W. (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - "Mormon Doctrine in the United States" Submitted for the John Addison Porter Prize Pseudonym "Pipp", 1904-1905 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - "The Trent Affair" Submitted for the John Addison Porter Prize, 1905-1906 (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - A. Southerner, pseud. (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Norton Russell, pseud. (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Rasselas, pseud. (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Elyria, pseud. (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Japamerhist, pseud. (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Miles, Eugene Richard, pseud. "The Rise of the Federalist Party in the South" Essay submitted for the John Addison Porter Prize, 1905-1906 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - "The Liberation of Cuba" Essays submitted for the John Addison Porter Prize, 1904-1905 (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - Adams, Frederick Leonard (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - Hull, Albert Wallace Y.1905 (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - Rooney, Francis (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - "Suffrage Provisions in Southern Constitutions" Essay submitted for the John Addison Porter Prize George Norwood (pseud.), 1906-1907 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - "The Annexation of Hawaii" Submitted for the John Addison Porter Prize, 1906-1907 (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - Publius Secundus, pseud. (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - Thomas Butler, pseud. (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - Paul Jones, pseud. (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - "William E. Seward" Submitted for the John Addison Porter Prize, 1906-1907 (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Cliesthenes, pseud. (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Caesar Borgia, pseud. (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Patch Work, pseud. (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Neeser, Robert W. "The Trent Affair", First Prize Essay submitted for the John Addison Porter Prize. 193 pp, 1906 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Augustine, Floyd A. "The Constitutional Aspects of the Acquisition of Louisiana" First Prize Essay submitted for the John Addison Porter Prize. 16 pp, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - Hendrick, T. K. "A study … of the Relative Efficiency … of Broken Stone … when used as an Aggregate in Concrete…" 84 pp, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - Hill, R. J., Jr. Y.1914 "The Expression of Mysticism in Modern Music" Submitted for John Addison Porter Prize (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Author unidentified "Christian Science". Essay submitted for John Addison Porter Prize, undated (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Nicholson, Marjorie H. "The Life and works of Henry Moore D.D." Chs 1-7. Prize essay submitted for John Addison Porter Prize, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 80A)
  - Nicholson, Marjorie H. "The Life and Works of Henry Moore D.D. Chs 8-13. Prize Essay submitted for John Addison Porter Prize, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 80B)
  - Submissions for Henry P. Wright Memorial Prize, Circa 1913-1928 (Box 9, Folder 81)
    - Buzzell, P. B. Y.1913 (Box 9, Folder 81)
    - Newman, Anstey (Box 9, Folder 81)
    - Sirrsky, Leon Y.1927 (Box 9, Folder 81)
    - Dwyer, George B. Y.1925 (Box 9, Folder 81)
    - Ingham, Travis Y.1928 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - Submissions for Henry P. Wright Memorial Prize, Circa 1930-1936 (Box 9, Folder 82)
    - Stevenson, Stuart S. (Box 9, Folder 82)
    - Converse, Allan (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Submissions for Philo Sherman Bennett Prize, 1913, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 83)
    - Wilder, Amos Y.1917 (Box 10, Folder 83)
    - Coffman, -- (Box 10, Folder 83)
    - Ford, D. K. (Box 10, Folder 83)
    - Johnson, John H. Y.1914 (Box 10, Folder 83)
    - Collins, J. F. (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Essays submitted for the Andrew D. White Prize in the Department of History, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 84)
    - Steinhardt, Frederick J. Y.1931 (Box 10, Folder 84)
    - Johnson, Howard P. Y.1931 (Box 10, Folder 84)
    - Clark, Roger W. Y.1931 (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Essays submitted for the Andrew D. White Prize in the Department of History, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 85)
    - Langmuir, Charles L. Y.1930 (Box 10, Folder 85)
    - Bestor, Arthur E., Jr. Y.1930 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Haskins, Caryl P. "Feudal Elements in Pre-Norman Scottish Law" Submitted for the Andrew White Prize, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - Essays submitted for the Andrew D. White Prize in the Department of History, 1925-1927 (Box 10, Folder 87)
    - Caudee, M. C., Y.1925 (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - Essays submitted for the Andrew D. White Prize in the Department of History - three essays, Authors unidentified, 1922 (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - Essays submitted for the Lloyd Mifflin Prize, 1921 (Box 10, Folder 89)
    - Copeland, Thomas (Box 10, Folder 89)
    - Vance, Thomas H. Y.1921 (Box 10, Folder 89)
    - West, Harold A. (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - Riegen, Deric "Existentialist Thought and Expressionist Poetry" Submitted for the John Addison Porter Prize. 51 PP, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 90)
  - Nolan, Frank P. Y.1900 (Box 10, Folder 91)
    - "The Nicaragua Canal" (Box 10, Folder 91)
    - Essay submitted for the William C. Tucker Prize, 1900 (Box 10, Folder 91)
  - Klein, Roy A. "Design for a Sewerage System for Thompsonville, Connecticut" Submitted for William C. Tucker Prize, 1906 (Box 10, Folder 92)
  - Ord, Herbert J. Y.1904S "Specification for the Structural Ironwork of an office building" Submitted for William C. Tucker Prize, 1907? (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - Luce, Robert F. Y.1910S "Design for a Sewer System for the town of Ipswich, Massachusetts" Submitted for William C. Tucker Prize (Box 11, Folder 95)
  - Rosenburg, Julius M. Y.1911S "Investigation and Improvement of a Plant for the Removal of Iron in a Public Water System" Submitted for William C. Tucker Prize (Box 11, Folder 96)
  - Levine, M. H. Y.1912S "West Hartford Sanitary Sewerage System" Submitted for William C. Tucker Prize (Box 11, Folder 97)
  - Wolff, Fred. M. Y.1932S "Ford-Rouge-A-1016" 13pp Submitted for the Industrial Research Prize, undated (Box 11, Folder 98)
  - Zalkan, George Y.1931S "A Worker Looks at Organized Labor" Submitted for Yale Industrial Research Prize, undated (Box 11, Folder 99)
  - Roberts, Harry Walter "The Heartless Worker" 27 pp Submitted for Yale Industrial Research Prize, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 100)
  - Davies, Everett F. S. "Harsh Symphony: A Summer's Experience at the Ford Motor Company" 38 pp Submitted for Yale Industrial Research Prize, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 101)
  - Dobbins, Kemper A. Y.1932 "Facts about the Ford Worker" 35 pp Submitted for Yale Industrial Research Prize (Box 11, Folder 120)
  - Sawyer, R. Brockunier Y.1932 "Industrial Relations at the Plant" Submitted for Yale Industrial Research Prize 18 pp, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 103)
  - Zendt, Oliver M. "Henry Ford: The Virtues of the Man and his Industry" Submitted for the Yale Industrial Research Prize, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 104)
  - Sears, Richard "Personnel Problems in the Ford Motor Company" Submitted for the Yale Industrial Research prize, 0 pp, undated (Box 11, Folder 105)
  - Marcus, Morris L. Y.1928 "What Prize Industry" 32 pp Submitted for the Yale Industrial Research Prize (Box 11, Folder 106)
  - Mimms, Thomas B. "My Adventure in Industry" 40 pp Submitted for the Yale Industrial Research Prize, 1925? (Box 11, Folder 107)
  - Li, C. N. "A Second Summer in the Ford Motor Company" Submitted for the Yale Industrial Research Prize, 1926 (Box 11, Folder 108)
  - Li, C. N. "A Summer in the Ford Motor Company" Submitted for the Yale Industrial Research Prize, undated (Box 11, Folder 109)
  - Hilgard, Ernest R. "A Challenge to Democracy" 15 pp Submitted for Yale Industrial Research Prize, 1926 (Box 11, Folder 110)
  - Fleming, E. McCluny "A Summer in Detroit Industry" 34 pp Submitted for Yale Industrial Research Prize, undated (Box 11, Folder 111)
  - Ackley, Ernest "Our Industrial System at its Best" 20 pp Submitted for Yale Industrial Research Prize, 1929 (Box 11, Folder 112)
  - Cornish, W. A. Y.1987 "Problems submitted for the Senior Mathematics Prize" 13 pp, 1887 (Box 12, Folder 113)
  - Leffingwell, Frank D. Y. 1887 "Problems submitted for the Senior Mathematics Prize" 14 pp (Box 12, Folder 113)
  - Lyne, Henry "Problems submitted for Senior Mathematics Prize." 36 pp, 1887 (Box 12, Folder 114)
  - Rogers, Miriam N. S. "Strangers of Athens" Thesis Rejected? 43 pp, 1895 (Box 12, Folder 115)
  - Anton, George F. "Power Factor Correction" 62 pp Rejected Thesis of Master of Science, 1925 (Box 12, Folder 116)
  - Unidentified "Some Aspects of the Venetian School of Painting" 35 pp, undated (Box 12, Folder 117)
  - Unidentified "The Sepoy Mutiny" 15 pp, undated (Box 12, Folder 118)
  - Unidentified "The Acceptance of the Copernican Theory" 16 pp, undated (Box 12, Folder 119)
  - Unidentified "The Chartist Movement" 24 pp, undated (Box 12, Folder 120)
  - Unidentified "The Rise of the Town as Affecting Literature and Music" 25 pp, undated (Box 12, Folder 121)
  - Bradley, Frederick D. "The Historical Significance of the Revocation of the Edict of Nantes" 26 pp, 1925 (Box 12, Folder 122)
  - Madden, Arthur C. Y.1942 "Financial Statement Analysis of Pennsylvania Salt Company and International Salt Company for year 1938-1940" 19 pp, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 123)
  - Dunlap, R. D. Y.1945 "Decisions of Timothy Dwight, 1813-1814" 6 pp, undated (Box 12, Folder 124)
  - Hale, William "Cooperative Consumers of New Haven, Inc. A Grocery Coop. Religious Programs for Social Action" 7 pp, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 125)
  - Stevens, Charles Leigh "Military Mapping" 14 pp, undated (Box 12, Folder 126)
  - Macdonald, Ross B. "Reference to Maps and Geographers during the Roman Empire, including quotations from various Books, notes, and comments by the editor" 26 pp, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 127)
  - Streibert, Marshall G. Y.1960 "The Relationship of Moslem Mapmaking and the West" 5 pp (Box 12, Folder 128)
  - Term Papers; Economics Courses of Clive Day, 1931 (Box 12, Folder 129-130)
    - Black, Lester H (Box 12, Folder 129-130)
    - Brooks, Robert. R. R. (Box 12, Folder 129-130)
    - Colburn, Elizabeth L. (Box 12, Folder 129-130)
    - Chapman, Stuart W. (Box 12, Folder 129-130)
    - Edmiston, Henry E. (Box 12, Folder 129-130)
    - Gabriel, Germain J. (Box 12, Folder 129-130)
    - Gertner, Abraham (Box 12, Folder 129-130)
    - Gorski, R. S. (Box 12, Folder 129-130)
    - Lee, Frances (Box 12, Folder 129-130)
    - Wolf, J. (Box 12, Folder 129-130)
  - Honors Theses presented at Sloane Laboratory (Box 12, Folder 131)
    - Pratt, Howard J, 1886 (Box 12, Folder 131)
    - Brownell, H. B., 1888 (Box 12, Folder 131)
    - Lincoln, C. W., 1888 (Box 12, Folder 131)
    - Pond, S. V., 1889 (Box 12, Folder 131)
    - Colles, George W., Jr., 1892 (Box 12, Folder 131)
    - Gibbons, M. J., 1897 (Box 12, Folder 131)
    - Ewell, Arthur W., 1897 (Box 12, Folder 131)
    - Spencer, Paul, undated (Box 12, Folder 131)
  - Wakefield, Leander E. Y.1842 "The Eternity of Memory" 22 pp, 1840 (Box 13, Folder 133)
  - Abbott, Morris W. "Notes on the Life of Edward Rodolphus Lambert" 19 pp, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 134)
  - Heller, Fred "John L. O'Sullivan: His Magazine and His Doctrine of Manifest Destiny" 29 pp, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 135)
  - Kahn, Marc "The Origins of City Planning in New Haven" 46 pp, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 136)
  - Chapman, Paul D. "German Influence on the Development of Yale College to 1861" 54 pp, 4 appendices, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 137)
  - Robb, John D. "The Revival of 1831 at Yale" 43 pp, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 138)
  - Laventhal, David A. Y.1957 "Government Control and Education in Communist China" 38 pp, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 139)